Guide to the Carolina Wren Press Records, 1940-1994, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Carolina Wren Press: Judy Hogan Papers Series
  - Writings Subseries, ca. 1970-1990 and undated
    - Love/Fight (Box 72)
    - Mature Stones (Box 72)
    - Measuring Rods in a Less Than Visionary Age (Box 72)
    - Messages of Gold (Box 72)
    - Mother as Leader (Box 72)
    - My Neighbors And My Children's Neighbors (Box 72)
    - My Small Press And My Public Library (Box 72)
    - My Work/Job (Box 72)
    - The Nectar of the Gods (Box 72)
    - New Love Poems (Box 72)
    - NewWorld (Box 72)
    - Nobody's Perfect: An Attempt to Describe the Fiction of Curt Johnson (Box 72)
    - Notebook of a Female With PhD Aspirations, Vol. IV. (Box 72)
    - Oklahoma Home (Box 73)
    - Old Notebook (Box 73)
    - On Being a Carolina Wren (Box 73)
    - Out of the Dark Nest (Box 73)
    - A Partner/A Friend, Ch. VI (Box 73)
    - Passing Through Zero (Box 73)
    - Poems to Hamar, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Poetry and Four-Year Olds (Box 73)
    - Raccoons (Box 73)
    - Reply to Robert Bly (Box 73)
    - The Sages of Rougemont (Box 73)
    - Scrapbook of Technical Devices (Box 73)
    - Selling Apples Off the Main Road (Box 73)
    - Shades of Socrates! (Box 73)
    - Simplify! Simplify! (Box 73)
    - Soviet Exchanges (Box 73)
    - The Spring at Rougemont (Box 73)
    - Stone Soup for One (Box 73)
    - Stone Soup in a Nuclear Age (Box 73)
    - The Strait of Juan de Fuca (Box 73)
    - Sun-Blazoned, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Suzannah, Teach Me to Love/Grace, Sing to Me, (4 folders) (Box 73)
    - That Ecstatic Dance (Box 73)
    - This New and Gorgeous Garment (Box 73)
    - Majesty: An Idea of Manhood (Box 73)
    - Using the Creative Process as a Touchstone For Teaching Adults (Box 73)
    - Using "The Mother of Transformations" to Get The Job Done (Box 73)
    - Watering the Roots of a Democracy, (8 folders) (Box 73)
    - What Carolina Wren Means to Me (Box 73)
    - What Happened at Rougemont (Box 73)
    - Where Do I Write? (Box 73)
    - Where Is All This Energy To Go? (Box 73)
    - Why Do Old Men Need Their Sons and Grown Men Need Their Fathers? (Box 73)
    - Why I Return to Rougemont (Box 73)
    - Why We Need Our Network (Box 73)
    - Wild Nasturtiums (Box 73)
    - Women and the Small Press Movement. (Box 73)
    - Miscellaneous early poetry, 1958-1974; undated; (6 folders) (Box 73)
    - Reviews, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Novel: Vol. III (Box 73)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Books XII-XIV (Box 73)
    - Carolina Wren Press: Flying Against the Wind (Box 73)
    - Four I's Volume One, "As Easily as the Sun" (Box 73)
    - Hogan (Box 73)
    - Interviews With Roland Alston, (4 folders) (Box 73)
    - Restart Eight Plus, Book XXV Overton (Box 73)
    - Southern Poetry, Return of the Bougainvillaea Vision (Box 73)
    - Small Presses and the Library (Box 73)
    - Sun-Blazoned, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - The Sun, Doorways (Box 73)
    - The Sun, Journal (Box 73)
    - Suzannah, Teach Me to Love/Grace, Sing To Me (Box 73)
    - Journal, The Poem as Rush/Muse/Given (Box 73)
    - Miscellaneous Writings and Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Interviews (Box 74)
  - Teaching Material Subseries, ca. 1980-1991 and undated
    Class notes, student work, writing games and assignments, and photocopies of readings used in classes taught by Judy Hogan.
    - Teaching materials (Box 75)
    - Teaching materials: Roadmaps (Box 76-77)
  - Financial Papers Subseries, ca. 1970-1985 and undated
    Chiefly bills and cancelled checks belonging to Judy Hogan.
    - Financial papers (Box 78)
  - Biographical Material Subseries, ca. 1950s-1990 and undated
    Resumés, articles about Judy Hogan, astrological charts, schoolwork, college notebooks, and an application for a residency.
    - Biographical material (Box 79)
    - Biographical material: College notebooks (Box 80)
  - Oversize Materials Subseries
    - Correspondence, 1971-1980 (I:13) (Box 81)
    - Whole COSMEP Catalog, 1973 (I:13) (Box 81)
    - Clippings regarding Carolina Wren Press and associated presses, 1972-1990 and undated (Box 81)
    - Lollipop Power Press: Illustrations and clippings regarding its publications, 1975and undated (Box 81)
    - Page proofs of Rainbow Roun Mah Shoulder, by Linda Brown Bragg, ca. 1984 (Box 81)
    - Posters advertising classes, workshops, fellowships, and competitions; book jackets, 1975-1991 and undated (I:14) (Box 81)
- Accessions, (10 boxes, 2 oversize folders)
  Most of these accessions are unprocessed. Many contain restricted materials and are not available for research until full processing. Contact Research Services with questions about this collection.
  Collection restrictions may apply to unprocessed accessions. Please contact Research Services in advance with questions about using this material.
  - Accession 99/369
    Includes: clippings, correspondence, bound volumes (short stories, poetry) from CWP, business records, promotional materials, manuscripts. Restrictions may apply.
    - Unsorted materials (Box 1-2, Acc. 99/369)
    - Oversize folder (Box 1-2, Acc. 99/369, Folder 1, Acc. 99/369)
  - Accession 06/109 (Box 1-2, Acc. 06/109)
    This addition comprises book covers and book cover proofs, edited copies and proofs of writings by and correspondence concerning the work of Carolina Wren authors/poets: Andrea Selch, Elaine L. Goolsby, William Henry Lewis, Preston Allen, Dava Walker, and George Elliott Clark. The addition also includes business records of the Carolina Wren Press, board meeting records and advertising and publicity.
  - Accession 07/065 (Box 1-5, Acc. 07/065)
  - Accession 11/1006 (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Public information, etc., 1989-1990 (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Administrative files, board meetings, agendas, pre-1992 (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Administrative files, board meetings, agendeas, 1992-1994, (3 folders) (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Christina's Toolbox (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Family Meal (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Jokes (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Journey Proud (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Keep the Killer Asleep (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Puzzles (Box 1, Acc. 11/1006)
    - Cover designs (Opaperfolder 1, Acc. 11/1006)